Guide to the Motion picture press kit collection, 1968-2004
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Motion picture press kit collection
1968-2004
C0107
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
10 linear feet (16 boxes)
This collection contains hundreds of motion picture press kits donated by George Mason University English professors Peter Brunette, Jr. and Margaret R. Yocom. The press kits promote foreign as well as domestic films, mostly from the past two decades, and range in format from glossy, full-color booklets to packets printed out in black and white and stapled together.
Margaret Yocom
Peter C. Brunette, Jr.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Peter C. Brunette and Margaret Yocom in 1999.
Historical Information
Press kits are packets of printed material distributed to promote the release of a forthcoming film. They often include photographs along with text promoting the film and providing information on actors, directors, and producers. Press kits can range from glossy, full-color booklets to loose assemblages of photographs, slides, and stapled packets of information. Since distribution of expensive, full-color press kits is often limited to industry leaders (critics, promoters, etc.), press kits can be quite collectable, particularly for Hollywood blockbusters that have stood the test of time and successful independent features. This collection of motion picture press kits was assembled by Margaret Yocom, a George Mason University professor of folklore who has written film reviews for academic journals, and Peter C. Brunette, a GMU professor of English and film studies who served on the International Critics' Jury at the Bangkok International Film Festival.
Scope and Content
This collection contains hundreds of motion picture press kits donated by George Mason University English professors Peter Brunette, Jr. and Margaret R. Yocom. The press kits range in format from glossy, full-color booklets to packets printed out in black and white and stapled together. Several press kits also include promotional photographs and color slides. The collection is divided into three series, grouping press kits, correspondence and other papers related to the film industry, and oversized promotional material together.
Series 1 contains several hundred press kits for a variety of films, including major studio and independent releases. The press kits promote foreign as well as domestic films from the past two decades. The professionally printed materials include press kits for "Bandit Queen," "Japon," "Europa," "Dancer in the Dark," "Brother's Keeper," "The Piano," "Antz," "Todo Sobre Mi Madre," "The English Patient," "Eternity and a Day," "The Road to Perdition," "Muriel's Wedding," and "The Straight Story." Some press kits include handwritten notes and reviews, along with articles published in major newspapers and trade magazines about the films.
Series 2 contains miscellaneous documents pertaining to the movie industry. Included is "A Guide to Self Distribution", detailing the challenges faced by independent movie producers. Also included in this series are mailings from movie studios and schedules of upcoming releases.
Series 3 contains oversized promotional film material. Some material is accompanied by its printed press kit. The oversized promotional items in this series include a promotional package for the film "Barb Wire" with a copy of the original comic book, and an original souvenir booklet produced for the release of "2001: A Space Odyssey".
Arrangement
Series 1: Films, 1988-2004 (Box 1-15)
Series 2: Miscellaneous, 1988-2004 (Box 15)
Series 3: Oversize, 1968-2000 (Box 16)
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds many performing arts collection, some which contain information on films and film promotion, particularly film posters from East Germany.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Pressbooks.; Motion picture industry.
Contents List
- Series 1: Films, 1988-2004
  This series contains hundreds of press kits for both major studio and independently released films. Several press kits were printed for film festivals and contain promotional photographs and slides as well as printed information. Press kits range from professionally produced booklets, to CD-ROM format, to simple print outs.
  - Pi, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes a cast and crew list with brief biographies and a short synopsis of the film.
  - 8 Women, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Promotional booklet for the 2002 Berlin International Film Festival, and printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, film synopsis, and soundtrack information.
  - 8 and a Half Women, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Promotional pamphlet for the 1999 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Aberdeen, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - The Accompanist, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, film synopsis, and soundtrack information.
  - The Addiction, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Film synopsis with photocopied movie poster.
  - The Adventures of Priscilla, Queen of the Desert., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, film synopsis, and soundtrack information. Also contains an invitation to the Cannes '94 midnight screening and pre-screening party, four promotional slides, and promotional articles.
  - After Life, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Also includes three promotional film stills.
  - Afterglow, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Alice et Martin, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, film synopsis. Two promotional slides.
  - All About my Mother, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Color booklet featuring detailed synopsis, directors comments, and cast and crew biographies.
  - All the Real Girls, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - A ma soeur!, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Full color promotional booklet for the 2001 Berlin International Film Festival.
  - Les Amants du Pont-Neuf, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    French promotional booklet with film synopsis, and cast and crew list.
  - Amelie, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Amen, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Includes two large color promotional booklets including: film synopsis, interviews with director and actors, biographies of cast and crew, timeline with overview of the historical period in which the film is set, and reactions and information about the original play and playwright. Also included is a film review from the New York Times.
  - The American Astronaut, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Psycho, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - L'amore Molesto, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Two color promotional booklets in both English and French.
  - Angles and Insects, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Printed material including a film synopsis and information on selected cast members. Also includes three sheets of hand written notes on the film.
  - Antz, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Color promotional booklet including synopsis, cast and crew information and interviews.
  - Apocalypse Now (Redux), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Printed material detailing differences from original release.
  - L'appartement, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, film synopsis, and soundtrack information. Also includes a photocopy of a 1996 Variety article on the film.
  - The Apple, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Promotional color booklet made for the 1998 Cannes Film Festival. Printed in both French and English.
  - Artemisia, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Printed material includes an interview with the director, information on cast and crew and a synopsis of the film. Also included are notes from Art Historian Mary Garrard challenging the historical accuracy of the film.
  - The Autumn Heart, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, and Balserosfilm synopsis.
  - The Baby of Macon, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, film synopsis. Also includes two promotional photographs.
  - Balseros, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Synopsis of film and two photocopied Spanish articles.
  - Bandit Queen, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Promotional color booklet printed for the 1994 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Beau Travail, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Promotional booklet printed for the 1999 Venice International Film Festival printed in English, French, and Italian.
  - Beaumarchais the Scoundrel, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, film synopsis, and historical information relevant to the film.
  - Beautiful People, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Beautiful Thing, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Before Night Falls, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographieS, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Beijing Bicycle, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Color booklet printed for the Berlin International Film Festival.
  - Belle Epoque, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - La Belle Noiseuse, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Promotional booklet with brief synopsis, and cast and crew information. Printed in both English and French.
  - Bend It Like Beckham, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, film synopsis.
  - Betelnut Beauty, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Promotional color booklet printed for the Belin International Film Festival.
  - Better than Sex, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Big Night, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, film synopsis. Also includes two promotional photographs.
  - The Blair Witch Project, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list including biographies and interviews, selected filmographies, film synopsis, and soundtrack information. Also includes information the "history" of the Blair Witch and the events in the movie.
  - Bloody Morning, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Four promotional photographs.
  - Blow, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Contains two promotional packets, one detailing the movie and another titled "A Brief Primer on Cocaine and Cartles".
  - Bon Voyage, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Boyz n the Hood, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Breaking the Waves, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Promotional color booklet printed for the 1996 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Brother, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Brother's Keeper, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, film synopsis, three promotional photographs, flyers and post cards. Copies of movie reviews from Variety, the New York Times, the International Herald and Premiere are also included.
  - Bruce Almighty, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Promotional color booklet printed including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Buffalo '66, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cabaret Balkan, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Carrington, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Printed booklet includes detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Four black and white promotional photographs and three color slides are also included.
  - Cat in the Hat, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Catch Me If You Can, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Color promotional booklet including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Casa De Los Babys, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Also contains 9 color slides.
  - Chunhyang, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The Celebration, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Promotional color booklet printed for the 1998 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Central Station, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - The Celluloid Closet, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Character, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Chasing Amy, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Children of the Revolution, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chungking Express, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Cider House Rules, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Circle, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - La Ciudad (The City), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Clean, Shaven, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clerks, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cold Mountain, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Colonel's Children, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, film synopsis, and historical information relevant to the film. Also includes one promotional photograph.
  - The Color of Paradise, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Coming to Terms with the Dead, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Newspaper review of the film and printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Comment j'ai tue mon pere, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Connie and Carla, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Also includes CD-ROM with promotional images.
  - The Cooler, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - El Crimen del Padre Amaro, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Crimson Gold, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Cradle Will Rock, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Promotional newspaper printed for the 1999 Cannes Film Festival. Printed in color, the newspaper includes: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Crash, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Includes printed material with detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis; also a promotional booklet printed for the 1996 Cannes Film Festivle.
  - The Cruise, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Also includes a sheet of hand written notes.
  - Crumb, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cyclo, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Dancer (Billy Elliot), 2000 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Full color promotional booklet.
  - Dancer in the Dark, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Printed material including cast and crew information, and film synopsis. Includes twelve oversized cards featuring film stills, and one CD-ROM with additional stills.
  - Dark City, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Includes three promotional photographs.
  - Das Experiment, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Dawn of the Dead, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    File Plan note
    Full color booklet including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. One CD-ROM with film stills.
  - Denise Calls Up, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Distant, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dogma, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, interviews, and film synopsis. Also includes four pages of handwritten notes.
  - Dogville, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Promotional booklet including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, interviews, and film synopsis. CD-ROM with film stills and four color photographs.
  - La double vie de Veronique, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Promotional booklet printed for the 1991 Cannes Film Festival.
  - The Dreamlife of Angels, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - East is East, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The Eighth Day, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Printed Material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Elizabeth, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Printed including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, historical content relevant to the film, and film synopsis. Also includes a set of oversized tarot cards, printed with film stills and character information.
  - Eloge de L'amour, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Emperor and the Assassin, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The Emperor's Club, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Includes a CD-ROM with film stills.
  - The Empty Mirror, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Endurance: Shackleton's Legendary Antarctic Expedition, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Eight promotional black and white photographs.
  - The English Patient, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Color promotional booklet.
  - Enigma, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Envy, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    CD-ROM press kit.
  - Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, interviews, and film synopsis.
  - Eternity and a Day, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Color promotional booklet. Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis.
  - Eureka, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Europa, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, interviews, and film synopsis. Three black and white promotional photographs.
  - Eurotrip, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Eve's Bayou, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Eye of God, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Everybody's Fine, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, interviews, and film synopsis. Includes seven color slides.
  - Family Portrait, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Far From Heaven, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, interviews, and film synopsis. Six sheets of black and white, and color photographs.
  - Farewell my Concubine, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, interviews, and film synopsis. Promotional color booklet and several promotional photographs.
  - Fast, Cheap and Out of Control, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Felicia's Journey, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, interviews, and film synopsis. Color booklet printed for the 1999 Cannes Film Festival.
  - Felix et Lola, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Festival in Cannes, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fiorile, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Flower of my Secret, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Forever Fever (That's the Way I Like It), 1998 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Frat House, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Full Monty, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The General, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Genial Mes Parents Divorcent!, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Georgia, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Promotional booklet printed for the 2000 Cannes Film Festival. Two black and white photographs, and slides.
  - Germinal, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ghost Dog: The Way of the Samurai, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Girl With a Pear Earring, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - God is Great, I'm Not, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - God Said, "Ha!", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Gods and Monsters, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Gods and Monsters, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - The Golden Bowl, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Promotional color booklet.
  - The Great Pumpkin, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Article from Moving Pictures.
  - The Guys, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hana-Bi, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Promotional booklet printed for the 1997 Venice International Film Festival.
  - Happy Texas, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Happy Times, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Happy Together, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Harmonist, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Heavenly Creatures, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Hideous Kinky, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - High Art, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Hillary and Jackie, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Homicide, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Also includes black and white promotion photographs, and newspaper reviews of the film.
  - Homicide, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Screenplay.
  - Honey, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - The House of Mirth, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Production notes.
  - The House of Yes, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Household Saints, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Human Nature, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Color promotional booklet.
  - The Human Stain, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - I Can't Sleep, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - I Remember Me, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - I Shot Andy Warhol, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - An Ideal Husband, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Il mio viaggio in Italia, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - In America, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Two black and white promotional photographs and four color slides.
  - In the Company of Men, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Promotional booklet for the 1997 Cannes Film Festival.
  - In the Cut, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Innocence, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Four black and white promotional photographs.
  - Intolerable Cruelty, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. CD-ROM with promotional film stills.
  - Irma Vep, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Promotional booklet printed in French and English.
  - Irreversible, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Promotional booklet with film stills, cast and crew information, and production timeline.
  - Italian for Beginners, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Japon, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Jerusalem, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Jerry and Tom, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Jesus' Son, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Joe the King, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Jude, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, and film synopsis. Four promotional black and white photographs.
  - Junk Mail (Budbringeren), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Kanehsatake: 270 Years of Resistance, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Printed material including: detailed cast and crew list, selected filmographies, film synopsis, and historical content relevant to the film. Three promotional photographs.
  - Keep the River on Your Right: A Modern Cannibal Tale, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Kicking and Screaming, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Kill Bill Vol. 1, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - The King is Alive, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Kira's Reason - A Love Story (En karlighedshistorie), 2001 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Kolya, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - L. 627, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 23)